We unfortunately cannot let people stay due to fire safety concerns.
很抱歉 由于火警安全问题 我们不能让人们留在这里
If you are standing at this time, please leave the... Wait, why'd you... Turn on the... You're not supposed to turn this on.
如果你现在站着 请离开...等等 为什么你...打开...你不应该打开的
Yes, that is supposed to be off.
是的 那应该是关闭的
Okay.
好的
Sorry, we do need everyone who's not currently seated to...
抱歉 我们确实需要所有目前没有坐下的人...
You may not sit in the aisles.
你不能坐在过道上
Hi, everyone. Welcome to 61B.
大家好  欢迎来到 61B
Woo!
哇！
So today we're gonna cover like a quick overview of how 6C1B goes.
今天我们将快速概述一下 61B 的内容
We'll go over a few bits of logistics and then we'll go over to Perrin to kind of explain or to do a bit of like Java 6C1A intro.
我们将讨论一些日常事务 然后过渡到 Perrin 来解释一下 或者做一些 Java 61B 的介绍
Before I get started, hi, I'm Justin.
在我开始之前 嗨 我是 Justin
This is Perrin.
这位是 Perrin
We're lecturers here, I guess.
我们在这里是讲师 我想
Anything you want to say?
有什么想说的吗？
No?
没有？
All right, great.
好的 太棒了
Awkward as ever.
一如既往地尴尬
What is this course about?
这门课程是关于什么的？
Well, overall, 6UMB is kind of a course.
总的来说 61B算是一门课程
It's not just a course about programming.
它不仅仅是一门关于编程的课程
6UMA was mostly there to teach you how do you program.
61A 主要是为了教你怎么编程
6UMB is going to be teaching you how do you program well.
61B 将教你如何编写高效的程序
So it's kind of an engineering class where you're given a set of things that you can do.
所以这有点像一门工程课 你会得到一些可以做的事情
And your goal is to kind of not just make something that works, but make something that works efficiently.
你的目标不仅是做出一个能工作的东西 而且是做出一个能高效工作的东西
So in this class, we'll be covering a lot of good algorithms, a lot of good data structures.
所以在这门课上 我们将涵盖很多好的算法 很多好的数据结构
Data structures are these kinds of structures that happen to be very useful.
数据结构就是这些非常有用的结构
A lot of problems get solved by just using this particular object.
很多问题都可以通过使用这个特定的对象来解决
People have found them very useful. So we'll be kind of talking about those.
人们发现它们非常有用  所以我们会谈论一些相关的内容
We'll also be talking a bit about how you write code efficiently.
我们还会谈一些关于如何高效编写代码的内容
So it isn't just can you write code that's fast, but can you write the code quickly?
在编程中 不仅仅要写出高效的代码 还要能快速地编写代码
If you take five years to write a simple program, no matter how efficient it is, it's probably not useful by the time you finally finish writing it.
如果你花五年时间来写一个简单的程序 无论它有多高效 最终完成它的时候可能已经不再有用了
So we'll be using these new tools to design code, test code, debug code.
所以我们将使用这些新工具来设计代码 测试代码 调试代码
All of these tools tend to be used in modern industrial settings.
所有这些工具通常在现代工业环境中使用
So you'll be learning how you actually write code in real life.
所以你会学习如何在现实生活中实际编写代码
We will be covering things in Java.
我们将涵盖Java中的内容
That's kind of the programming language we use in this class, mostly because it's a very useful language in general.
这是我们这门课程中使用的编程语言 主要是因为它在一般情况下是非常有用的语言
But this is not the focus of the course. This is not a Java programming course.
但这不是课程的重点  这不是一门Java编程课程
This is a programming course taught in Java.
这是一门用Java教授的编程课程
We assume that everyone here has had a solid understanding of some programming fundamentals.
我们假设这里的每个人都对一些编程基础有扎实的了解
So if you've taken 61A, then you should be good.
所以如果你上过 61A 那你应该没问题
But you should have at least one semester of programming experience before coming into this course.
但是在上这门课之前 你应该至少有一个学期的编程经验
All right.
好的
So some other great features to 6UMB are we kind of cover a lot of different things.
所以 61B 还有一些其他很棒的特点 我们会涉及到很多不同的东西
So for one thing, 6UMB tends to be one of the most useful classes regarding any job interview you'll have.
因此 其中一个很重要的特点是 61B 倾向于是关于任何求职面试中最有用的课程之一
If you go to a job interview for any CS internship, you'll probably be asked questions similar to what we discussed in this class, a lot of data structure stuff with hash tables, binary search trees, graphs, Dijkstra's, you name it.
如果你去参加任何 CS 实习的面试 你可能会被问到类似我们在这门课上讨论过的问题
很多数据结构的内容 包括哈希表、二叉搜索树、图、Dijkstra 算法 等等
There's a lot of these cool things that you will end up learning.
有很多这些很酷的东西你最终会学到的
We also go over a lot of cool math.
我们还会讲很多很酷的数学
So we go over things like asymptotic analysis, seeing how quickly programs run.
所以我们会讲一些渐近分析 看看程序运行的速度有多快
We'll talk a lot about how arrays get resized and how we can actually get that in approximately constant time.
我们会经常讨论数组如何调整大小 以及我们如何在大约常数时间内实现这一点
2-3 trees, red-black trees, they seem like two completely different things at first, but then we show that they're actually the same thing.
2-3树 红黑树 起初它们看起来像是两个完全不同的东西 但后来我们会展示它们实际上是一样的
We'll cover a lot of graph theory.
我们会涉及很多图论
We'll end with some lighter stuff, just some fun material, some unsolved problems like P equals NP.
我们最后会讲一些轻松的东西 只是一些有趣的材料 一些未解决的问题 比如P=NP
We'll just do a few things like that.
我们只是做一些类似的事情
And our goal by the end of this course is that you can write a program from scratch for yourself.
而且我们在这门课结束时的目标是 你能够自己从头开始写程序
So right now in 61A, you've learned how to write a program given a starter code.
所以现在在 61A 你已经学会了如何在给定的起始代码的基础上编写程序
By the time you leave this class, I want everyone to be able to write a program just for fun because they have some problem they need to solve or because they just want to, I don't know, waste a weekend doing something.
在你离开这个班级的时候 我希望每个人都能够写一个程序 只是为了好玩 因为他们有一些问题需要解决 或者只是因为他们想要 我不知道 浪费一个周末做些什么
All right.
好的
So before we get started, we kind of like to have this survey of the class just to see how everyone is.
所以在我们开始之前 我们想要对班级进行一次调查 看看每个人的情况如何
So what do you all hope to gain from this class?
那么你们都希望从这门课中获得什么？
Any takers?
有人要吗？
What?
什么？
What did you say?
你说什么？
Job.
工作
Yes, you want a job.
是的 你想要一份工作
That's a good one.
这个笑话不错
Anything else?
还有其他事吗？
Does anyone else want something from this class?
这个班级还有人想要什么吗？
Yeah?
嗯？
Run your code efficiently.
高效地运行你的代码
Yes, that is great.
是的 那太棒了
Anything else?
还有什么吗？
Yeah?
嗯？
An A!
一个 A！
Let's see about that.
看看吧
Anything else?
还有其他事吗？
Yeah?
嗯？
Huh?
啊？
Coding from scratch?
从零开始编码？
Yeah, coding from scratch, that's a great idea.
是的 从零开始编码 这是个好主意
I see some chat on Zoom, greater intuition.
我在Zoom上看到一些聊天 直觉更强
I saw a 300-person Zoom room.
我看到了一个 300 人的 Zoom 房间
Are we out of space on Zoom?
Zoom 上的空间用完了吗？
We will figure this out eventually.
我们最终会搞清楚的
I don't know.
我不知道
All right.
好的
More space, yes.
需要更多空间 是吗？
All right.
好的
And we kind of also want to go over a survey.
我们还想做个调查
So everyone here, how many people here are freshmen?
在场的人 有多少是大一的？
Almost everyone.
几乎都是
Any sophomores in the mix?
有没有大二的？
A few people.
有几个
Any juniors?
有大三的吗？
Yeah.
是的
Any seniors?
有什么前辈吗？
Yeah.
是的
A few seniors.
有几位前辈
How many people are CS majors?
CS 专业的人有多少？
How many people are EE majors?
EE 专业的人有多少？
That's not as many people as I was expecting.
这并不像我预期的那么多
Who's neither CS nor E?
谁既不是CS也不是E？
All right.
好的
What is everyone doing?
大家在干嘛呢？
No, no, no.
不 不 不
That wasn't meant that way.
不是那个意思
I'm asking you, like, what majors are you in?
我是问你 就是 你们学的是什么专业？
Data science.
数据科学
Right. I forgot about data science.
好的  我忘了数据科学
How many people are in data science?
有多少人在数据科学？
OK. That explains it.
好的  这就解释了
Any other majors in here?
这里还有其他专业吗？
Applied math.
应用数学
Yes.
是的
I did math as an undergrad as well.
我本科也学过数学
Very fun.
非常有趣
Physics?
物理？
Huh?
嗯？
What is that?
那是什么？
Code finance.
编程金融
History.
历史
Yes.
是的
All right.
好的
And how many people have taken 61A?
那么有多少人上了61A课程？
Almost everyone.
几乎所有人
How many people have not taken 61A but a similar class in another place?
有多少人没有上61A 但在其他地方上了类似的课程？
A few of you.
你们中有几个
Any other programming classes?
还有其他的编程课吗？
Yeah?
嗯？
What class?
什么课程？
Another 61B.
又是61B
OK.
好的
You're in data structures right now.
你现在学的是数据结构
All right.
好的
How many people have learned programming in Python?
有多少人学会了Python编程？
Java?
Java？
JavaScript?
JavaScript？
C Sharp?
C Sharp？
C++?
C++？
All right, all right, any other big languages?
好的 好的 还有其他重要的语言吗？
MATLAB? No, that does not count as a language.
MATLAB？ 不 那不算一门语言
Huh?
啊？
Socket?
Socket？
Kotlin?
Kotlin？
Ooh, that's a little, haven't heard of that one in a while.
哦 这有点 好久没听说过了
Ruby?
Ruby？
Scala?
Scala？
HTML, yes.
HTML 是的
All right.
好的
Well, as you can tell by this very varied crowd, a lot of you are coming in from completely different backgrounds.
嗯 正如你们可以从这个非常多元化的人群中看出的那样 你们中很多人来自完全不同的背景
So I want to ask this.
所以我想问这个
How many people know someone in this class already?
有多少人已经认识这个班上的人了？
Most of you.
你们大多数人
Do you all have project partners?
你们都有项目伙伴吗？
Do you know people who are going to be your project partners?
你知道谁会成为你的项目合作伙伴吗？
Well, I suggest you learn someone, get to know someone today, if possible.
嗯 我建议你今天认识一些人 如果可能的话
Everyone's here.
大家都在这里
It's a great time, you know, get to know someone.
这是一个很好的时机 你知道的 去认识一些人
Yeah?
是吗？
Yeah.
是的
All right.
好的
Before we move on, can I ask that we not block the entryway there?
在我们继续之前 我能不能要求我们不要堵住入口？
We can't leave this area blocked due to the fire safety rules.
由于消防安全规定 我们不能把这个区域堵住
We are going to have to ask you to move out.
我们得请你们搬开了
All right.
好的
You got it? All right.
你明白了吗？ 好的
So let's talk a bit about logistics, shall we?
那么 让我们谈谈后勤 好吗？
So we're going to have multiple components in this course.
这门课会涉及到多个组件
Most of what you'll be doing is through homeworks or discussions.
大部分任务都是通过作业或讨论完成的
So we will have lectures.
我们会有讲座
Lecture attendance is optional.
参加讲座是可选的
You don't necessarily have to come here.
你不一定非要来这里
I personally never learned really well from lectures, so I just didn't show up to lectures most of the time when I took classes.
我个人从来没在讲座中学到太多 所以我上课的时候大部分时间都没去
But if you learn well through someone talking to you, that's great.
但如果你通过听别人说话学得好 那太棒了
Please show up to lectures. Go to Zoom.
请参加讲座  去Zoom
We'll be answering questions in person or online through that.
我们会亲自或在线通过那回答问题
Generally speaking, you'll learn a lot through doing.
一般来说 通过做可以学到很多
Programming is not something you can learn just from theory.
编程不是仅从理论就能学会的
You have to actually practice it.
你必须亲自实践
So you'll be getting a lot of experience with programming Java through your homeworks, your labs, your projects.
通过你的家庭作业、实验室和项目 你将获得大量Java编程经验
Discussion won't do direct programming, but you'll be discussing a lot about how to code effectively.
讨论不会直接进行编程 但你将会讨论如何有效地编码很多
You'll get to solve a lot of interesting problems throughout the semester.
整个学期你将有很多有趣的问题要解决
We have some homeworks that are really good.
我们有一些非常好的作业
We try to make our exam questions interesting.
我们尽量让我们的考试问题变得有趣
You'll have a lot of time to work in discussions.
你将有很多时间在讨论中工作
Generally speaking, you should expect to get your points through four different ways.
一般来说 你应该期望通过四种不同的方式获得你的分数
So we'll have these low-effort points through weekly surveys, course evaluations.
所以我们会通过每周调查和课程评估获得这些低功耗分数
Someone asked on Zoom if there's a way for people on Zoom to meet people.
有人在 Zoom 上问是否有办法让 Zoom 上的人们见面
Yes, we should have an ed post for partnerships.
是的 我们应该为合作伙伴关系发布一篇编辑帖子
So please introduce yourself there.
所以请在那里介绍一下自己
It'll be a great time to meet new people.
这将是一个认识新朋友的好机会
So generally speaking, you should expect to get these course evaluations or weekly surveys.
所以一般来说 你应该期望收到这些课程评估或每周调查
Everyone should get points for homeworks, projects, and labs.
每个人都应该为作业、项目和实验得到积分
Those are going to be higher effort, though, so you will have a bit more time.
不过那些会花费更多精力 所以你会有更多时间
This is where you'll get the most learning.
这是你会得到最多学习的地方
Exams are going to be a bit trickier.
考试可能会有点棘手
We expect an average of around 65%.
我们预计平均分会在65%左右
In fact, the way our policies work is if the average is less than 65%, we'll reduce the maximum score so it is 65%.
事实上 我们政策的运作方式是 如果平均分低于65% 我们将降低最高分 使其为65%
But if the score is above 65%, then you all keep the same score.
但如果分数高于65% 那么大家保持相同的分数
If everyone gets an A in this class, great.
如果每个人在这门课上都能得到A 那太好了
We do have some pacing points, which is just keeping up with stuff.
我们确实有一些进度点 就是跟上进度
We don't actually
其实我们不需要
It doesn't actually count towards anything if you're aiming for a B or above.
如果你的目标是B或以上 这其实不算什么
It's only to get you to a B minus.
这只是为了让你达到B-的水平
The main idea is that if you don't learn well through lectures, then you don't need to show up to lectures.
主要意思是如果你不适应听讲 那你就不需要来听讲了
It's fine.
没关系
But we do kind of want you to show that you actually can learn the material on your own.
但是我们确实希望你能证明你自己能够自学材料
So you need at least a B or so before this stops being relevant.
所以在这变得不相关之前 你至少需要B或更高的成绩
We've set the B2B plus threshold to be a 65% on exams and 95% on everything else.
我们已将B到B+门槛设置为65％的考试和95％的其他事项
So that's kind of to get you a sense of where we're aiming our grades for.
这样做主要是为了让你对我们的成绩目标有个大概了解
And this is all based on department requirements.
这完全是根据部门的要求
They get mad at us if we give too few or too many A's.
如果我们给出的A太少或太多 他们会生气的
If everyone does really well on exams, we'll fight the department or something.
如果每个人在考试中都表现得非常好 我们可能会和部门争吵什么的
I don't know.
我也不清楚
We'll figure it out.
我们会想出解决办法的
We'll get full details about this all on our website, so please read through that.
我们会在我们的网站上提供关于这一切的详细信息 请仔细阅读
We also have a lot of logistics about that, lateness policies.
我们也有很多关于此的后勤信息 迟到政策
Please go through all this before you move on to the rest of the course.
在你继续课程的其余部分之前 请仔细阅读所有这些内容
We get a lot of questions about this, about people clearly not reading that.
关于这个问题 我们收到了很多问题 有些人显然没有仔细阅读那些内容
And it is not fun sometimes.
有时候这并不好玩
We also have a lot of misconduct policies there.
我们在那里也有很多违纪政策
We don't have enough time to go over them.
我们没有足够的时间来详细介绍它们
But it is very sad when we have to tell a student that what they did violated our misconduct policy, and they didn't know it.
但是当我们不得不告诉一名学生 他们的行为违反了我们的违纪政策 并且他们并不知道时 这是非常令人难过的
We have to enforce the rule, unfortunately.
不幸的是 我们必须执行这个规定
So please read through that and follow it as best as you can.
所以请仔细阅读并尽量遵守
You have a good reason for it.
你有足够的理由这样做
If you have an emergency for more than 72 hours, please let us know.
如果你有紧急情况超过72小时 请告诉我们
We are here to help you get as best a score as possible.
我们在这里帮助你尽可能获得最好的分数
We don't want you to resort to any underhanded behaviors.
我们不希望你采取任何不正当手段
We don't want you to resort to getting overstressed, getting poor grades on your other classes.
我们不希望你为了应付这门课而变得过分紧张 影响到其他课程的成绩
Yeah.
是的
So here's a brief overview of how the class will go.
那么 这门课程将会如何进行 我们简要介绍一下
So we'll largely divide the class into three phases.
所以我们会将课程主要分为三个阶段
Phase one is going to be basically, how do you write code in Java?
第一阶段基本上是关于如何用Java写代码？
It's going to be the fastest-paced part of this class, and it's kind of to get you up to speed with how Java programming works, all the differences between Java and Python, and if you need just some general ideas on how you program effectively.
这将是整个课程中进度最快的部分 目的是让你迅速了解Java编程的工作原理 Java和Python之间的所有区别 以及如果你需要一些关于如何有效编程的一般性想法
We'll have homework zero that's due in two days' time.
我们会有第0次作业 两天后截止
And that's kind of our intro to Java homework.
这就是我们对Java作业的简介了
So we are hitting the ground running.
所以我们要迅速入门
This is a very front-loaded class.
这是一个非常前期的课程
So be prepared for this.
所以为此做好准备
After that, within weeks 5 to 10, we'll start going to phase 2, which is kind of where we'll get the meat of our topics, the data structures.
之后 在第5到第10周内 我们将开始进入第二阶段 这就是我们将深入研究的地方 也就是数据结构
And all of this is kind of just all of the small tools or tricks that we found useful as computer engineers.
而所有这些都只是我们作为计算机工程师发现有用的一些小工具或技巧
You'll have a lot of coding here.
你会在这里编写很多代码
It'll move moderately fast.
它会移动得相当快
You will have a bit more free time than Java, but you'll still largely be learning new things.
与Java相比 你会有更多的空闲时间 但你仍然会大部分时间学到新东西
So it'll be fairly quick-paced.
所以它会相当快节奏
All this work is going to be solo.
所有这些工作都将是独自完成的
until phase 3.
直到第三阶段
In phase 3, we'll move on to algorithms.
在第三阶段 我们将转向算法
And in this part of the class, we'll actually slow down a lot.
在课程的这一部分 我们将实际上放慢很多
A lot of the lectures at that point are going to be small things like how do you program effectively.
那时候的很多讲座都会涉及一些小技巧 比如如何有效地进行编程
They're not going to be on any exams or anything, but they are going to be useful for developing your abilities as engineers.
它们不会出现在任何考试中 但对于培养你作为工程师的能力是很有用的
The last project is going to be a partner project.
最后一个项目将是一个合作项目
You are required to have a partner for this project because we're trying to get you to learn how to collaborate with someone else.
你必须和另一个人合作完成这个项目 因为我们想让你学会如何与他人合作
So if you don't have a friend by the end of today or by the end of this week, start looking for one.
所以如果你今天或者这周末还没有找到朋友 开始寻找一个吧
It'll be very useful.
这会非常有用
It will be going at a slower pace, but that doesn't mean that the material is going to be any less important.
进度会比较慢 但这并不意味着材料会变得不那么重要
It is arguably the most important stuff, because it is the most transferable stuff that we will teach.
这可能是最重要的东西 因为这是我们将教授的最易传授的东西
All right, so before we move on, are there any questions?
好的 所以在我们继续之前 有没有任何问题？
Let me see.
让我看看
Yeah, I don't have any further slides.
是的 我没有更多的幻灯片
Any questions before we move on?
在我们继续之前有任何问题吗？
All right, Perrin.
好的 Perrin
Yeah.
是的
OK, hi.
好的 嗨
Good to be here.
很高兴在这里
And congratulations for making it in.
祝贺你成功入选
All right, so I'm going to write a couple of Java programs for you so we get familiar with the Java language.
好的 我要为你写几个Java程序 这样我们就能熟悉Java语言了
And yeah, let's do it.
是的 让我们开始吧
OK, so I will start by writing them in Python.
好的 我将首先用Python来写它们
If you have never seen Python before, that's totally OK.
如果你以前从未见过Python 那完全没问题
I'll just put it up there as a comparison.
我就把它放在那里作为一个比较
If you have coded in Java before, this might be a little bit boring.
如果你以前用过Java编程 这可能有点无聊
But hopefully, you'll learn something new.
但希望你能学到新东西
So let's give it a shot.
所以我们试一试
OK, so here I am. I'm going to write a hello world program in Python.
好的 我在这里  我要用Python写一个hello world程序
You ready?
准备好了吗？
Print hello world.
打印你好世界
Ooh, OK, so there it is.
哦 好的 就是这样
Now I'm going to try to write the exact same thing.
现在我要尝试写完全相同的东西
You're so easily impressed.
你真容易满足
We're trying to write the exact same thing in Java.
我们试着用Java写完全相同的东西
So the first thing I'll try is I'll take this program and copy-paste it into the Java interpreter.
所以我要尝试的第一件事是将这个程序复制粘贴到Java解释器中
Well, first, I guess I should run the Python program. Works fine.
嗯 首先 我想我应该运行Python程序  运行正常
Now I'll try to run the Java program.
现在我将尝试运行Java程序
And hopefully, it is not too surprising that we get an error.
希望不会太惊讶 我们会得到一个错误
I can't take programs from one language, copy-paste them into another language, and expect it to work.
我不能将程序从一种语言复制粘贴到另一种语言 然后期望它能正常工作
And so specifically, the error that it says is class interface enum or record expected.
具体来说 报错说的是期望类接口枚举或记录
So to translate a little bit, what Java is complaining about is that this code doesn't live in a class.
稍微翻译一下 Java抱怨的是这段代码没有放在一个类中
So Java is a language that cares very much about object-oriented programming.
Java是一种非常注重面向对象编程的语言
It really cares that all the code you write is in a class.
它确实很在乎你写的所有代码都在一个类中
So let's make a class.
所以让我们创建一个类
So the magic words I'm going to use to define a class are public class.
所以我要用来定义一个类的魔法词是public class
Then I'm going to name my class something.
然后我要给我的类取一个名字
I'll call it Hello World. But you could have called it something different.
我会叫它Hello World  但你也可以给它取个不同的名字
And then now I have a blank class.
然后现在我有了一个空白的类
So let's try running this and see what happens.
所以让我们试着运行一下看看会发生什么
I run again and it still doesn't work.
我再次运行 但仍然不起作用
Okay, so now it's saying main method not found.
好的 现在它说找不到主方法
Please define the main method as public static void mainstream args.
请将主方法定义为public static void mainstream args
Well, this is about the most useful error message in the history of error messages because all I have to do is take that thing they told me to write and copy paste it right there and well,
嗯 这是有史以来最有用的错误消息 因为我所要做的就是把他们告诉我的那个东西复制粘贴到那里 然后
At least it worked this time.
至少这次它工作了
So what I've written on the right is actually the equivalent of this on the left, the blank program.
所以我在右边写的实际上就是左边这个空白程序的等价物
So now that I have the blank program, I can finally print hello world.
所以现在我有了空白的程序 我终于可以打印出 'hello world'
So I'll write instead of print, the magic words in Java are system.out.println.
所以我会写 而不是打印 在Java中 魔术词是 system.out.println
Then I'll write hello world.
然后我会写 'hello world'
And I'll end it with a semicolon.
然后我会以分号结束它
And if everything goes well, we get hello world.
如果一切顺利 我们就会得到 'hello world'
So good. We've written our first Java program.
很好  我们已经写了我们的第一个Java程序
OK. If you keep applauding, I'll never get through all this stuff I have to cover.
好的  如果你一直鼓掌 我就没法顺利讲完所有我要讲的内容了
OK, so let's reflect on what we learned.
好的 那么让我们回顾一下我们学到了什么
And hopefully, this is not applause worthy.
希望这不值得鼓掌
I don't know.
我不知道
OK, so what we saw is that all code has to be part of a class.
好的 所以我们看到的是所有的代码都必须是类的一部分
Java cares a lot about being object-oriented.
Java 非常重视面向对象
That means everything you write has to be part of a class.
这意味着你写的所有东西都必须是类的一部分
We talked about the syntax for defining a new class.
我们谈论了定义新类的语法
You notice that instead of using whitespace, like indents,
你会注意到 我们不是用空格缩进
To say where things begin and end, we use brackets.
为了表示事物的起始和结束 我们使用大括号
You'll also notice that we ended lines with a semicolon.
你还会注意到我们用分号结束了每一行
These are all minor little syntax things that you'll pick up as you practice using Java, so don't worry about memorizing them.
这些都是一些小小的语法细节 在你练习使用Java的过程中 你会逐渐掌握的 所以不要担心要死记硬背它们
They'll become second nature to you before you even know it.
在你自己都没察觉的时候 它们会变成你的第二天性
OK, so that's my reflection on our first Hello World program.
好的 这是我对我们的第一个Hello World程序的反思
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的
No applause this time.
这次不用鼓掌了
OK, let's write some more programs.
好的 让我们再写一些程序
So this time, I'm going to write a program called Hello Numbers.
这次 我打算写一个名为Hello Numbers的程序
This one will be a little bit more complicated.
这个会稍微复杂一点
So this time, I'm going to try to print out the numbers between 0 and 10.
所以这次 我要试着打印出0到10之间的数字
So let's do that. So first, I'll say x equals 0.
那么我们就这样做吧  所以首先 我会说 x = 0
Don't applaud.
不要鼓掌
It's just x equals 0.
就只是 x = 0
Then I will say, while x is less than 10, I will print out x. And then I'll increment x to be 1 larger than before.
然后我会说 当 x < 10 时 我会打印出 x 然后我会把 x 增加到比之前大 1
And hopefully, this gives me some numbers between 0 and 10, so 0 through 9.
希望这样可以给我一些0到10之间的数字 所以是0到9
Now let's try to do this in Java.
现在让我们试着用Java来做这个
So I'll come over to Java.
所以我会转到Java
I've written the equivalent of the blank program for you ahead of time.
我提前为你写了等价的空白程序
And I'm going to try to just take this program and translate it to Java as close as I can.
我会尽量把这个程序翻译成Java
So I'll say x equals 0.
所以我会说x=0
Then I'll say while x is less than 10.
然后我会说当x<10时
I'll do the system.out.println x. And then I'll add 1 to x. So I took the program.
我会做system.out.println x 然后我会将x+1 所以我拿了这个程序
I tried my best to adapt it to Java.
我尽力将其调整到Java
And I run it.
然后我运行它
And it says error.
然后它显示错误
Cannot find symbol x. So it doesn't know where x is, which is kind of weird.
找不到符号x 所以它不知道x在哪里 有点奇怪
Isn't it right there?
不是就在那里吗？
So I don't know.
所以我不知道
Maybe we have to help Java find it and be like, it's right here.
也许我们必须帮助Java找到它 就像 它就在这里
But I don't think that's going to work either.
但我不认为那会起作用
So we're going to try it.
所以我们要尝试一下
OK, well, Java doesn't seem to like that either.
好的 嗯 Java 似乎也不喜欢那样
So the problem here is that in Java, before you can use a variable, you have to declare that it exists first.
所以问题在于 在 Java 中 在你使用一个变量之前 你必须先声明它存在
So what Java is expecting is first you have to say, I declare there is a variable called x, and it is of type integer.
所以 Java 预期的是 首先你要说 我声明有一个叫做 x 的变量 它是整数类型的
And only after I say that x exists
只有在我声明 x 存在之后
Can I actually use it?
我才能真正使用它？
So now that I declare X exists, now I can use it, and I print out 0 through 9.
所以现在我声明X存在 现在我可以使用它 然后我打印出0到9
So that's my Hello Numbers demo.
这就是我的Hello Numbers演示
Now, this seems like such a minor change.
现在 这似乎是一个如此微小的变化
So now when I want to use a variable, I have to declare that it exists and also say what type it is.
所以现在当我想要使用一个变量时 我必须声明它存在 并且还要说明它是什么类型
And this seems like a really minor change. But as you start using Java for more complicated programs, it turns out that just
而这似乎是一个非常微小的变化  但是 当你开始在Java中使用更复杂的程序时 事实证明
This little tiny change can have huge implications on how you write your program.
仅仅一个微小的变化可能会对你编写程序的方式产生巨大的影响
So for example, in Python, I can declare variables wherever I want.
比如说 在Python中 我可以随时声明变量
I can reassign them.
我可以重新分配它们
So later, I can say, actually, I think x is horse, and I can print x. And I'll get 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 horse.
所以后来 我可以说 实际上 我觉得x是horse 然后我可以打印x 我会得到1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、horse
But if I try the same trick in Java and I say, I think x should be horse now, and I try to system.out.println x,
但如果我在Java中尝试同样的花招 我说 我觉得x现在应该是horse 然后我尝试system.out.println x
Well, Java's going to say, you can't do that.
嗯 Java会说 你不能这样做
You told me that x is an integer, and you tried to reassign it to horse.
你告诉我x是一个整数 然后你试图重新分配它成为horse
You can't do that.
你不能这样做
That's incompatible types.
这是不兼容的类型
So in Java, because we are declaring x to be an integer, you can't reassign it to horse.
所以在Java中 因为我们声明x是一个整数 你不能将它重新分配给horse
And even if you tried to fool the Java compiler with some little trick like this, it'll say, you can't do that.
即使你试图用一些小技巧愚弄Java编译器 它也会说 你不能这样做
You already declared x to be an integer.
你已经声明x是一个整数
You can't change your mind.
你不能改变主意
It's already an integer.
它已经是一个整数
OK.
好的
So it seems like a tiny little change, but can have huge implications on how we write our programs.
看起来是一个微小的改变 但对我们编写程序的方式可能有巨大影响
So let's reflect again.
那么让我们再次反思一下
So before you can use a variable, you have to declare that it exists.
在使用变量之前 你必须声明它的存在
And when you declare the variable, you have to say, what type is it?
当你声明变量时 你必须说明它是什么类型的？
Is it an integer?
它是整数吗？
Is it a string?
它是字符串吗？
What kind of variable is it?
它是什么类型的变量？
And once you declare it, it can never change.
一旦你声明了它 它就永远不能改变
OK, so one other interesting observation that we can make here is that, well, it's not that type errors are unique to Java.
好的 还有一个有趣的观察是 不是只有Java才有类型错误
So yeah, here, the horse thing didn't compile, and that was only in Java.
所以在这里 horse的那部分在Java中无法编译通过
But some things don't compile in Python either.
但在Python中也有一些东西无法编译通过
So for example, if I tried to do horse plus 5 in Python, well, Python's not going to like that either.
比如说 如果我在Python中尝试执行horse加5 那么Python也不会喜欢这样做
It'll say 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
它会输出1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9
You cannot add horse and 5.
你不能把horse和5相加
OK, thank you, Python.
好的 谢谢 Python
And on this side, I could also try writing horse plus 5.
而且在这一边 我也可以尝试写horse+5
And do you notice anything a little bit interesting?
你有没有注意到什么有点有趣的地方？
This time, I still get the same error.
这次 我仍然得到了同样的错误
You can't add horse and 5. But this time, the code didn't even run.
你不能把horse和5加在一起  但这次 代码甚至都没运行
So I don't even see the 0 through 9.
所以我甚至没看到0到9
And in this case, the Java compiler looked at the code, analyzed it, and said, I'm refusing to run this code.
在这种情况下 Java编译器查看了代码 进行了分析 然后说 我拒绝运行这段代码
You have a tight bear.
你有一个严格的熊
You need to go fix it first.
你需要先修复它
So the kind of like mind blown observation here is that the program will check that all the types are good and that they check out before the program even runs.
所以这里令人震惊的观察是 程序会在运行之前检查所有类型是否正确
And that's in contrast to Python, where you can run the program and only when it encounters the type error does it crash and tell you that something has gone wrong.
这与Python相反 在Python中 你可以运行程序 只有当它遇到类型错误时 它才会崩溃 并告诉你出了什么问题
So that's the difference between Java and Python.
这就是Java和Python的区别
Java has static types.
Java具有静态类型
You have to declare variables and give them types, and Java will check them.
你必须声明变量并给它们赋类型 Java 会检查它们
Questions?
有问题吗？
OK, you're no longer impressed anymore.
好吧 你不再感到印象深刻了
I'm going to have to do juggling tricks or something to get more applause.
我得做点杂耍什么的才能得到更多掌声
OK, so now let's write one more Python-Java comparison, and then we'll do some more reflections.
好的 现在让我们再写一个 Python-Java 的比较 然后我们会做一些更深入的思考
This time, I'm going to write a function.
这一次  我要写一个函数
So I'm going to head into my Python place.
所以我要进入我的 Python 地方
Sorry, my mind blanked for a second.
抱歉 我脑子一片空白了一秒
And I'll write a function.
我会写一个函数
So I'll call it larger.
所以我会把它叫做更大
And I'll pass in two numbers.
我会传入两个数字
And this will return the larger of x and y. So hopefully I don't mess this up.
这将返回 x 和 y 中较大的那个 所以希望我不要搞砸
If x is greater than y, then I should return x. Otherwise, I'll return y. OK.
如果 x > y 那么我应该返回 x 否则 我会返回 y 好的
Looks good.
看起来不错
Now, let's try to use it for something.
现在 让我们试着用它做点什么
So maybe I'll say, I want to know what the larger is between negative 5 and 10.
也许我会说 我想知道-5和10之间哪个更大
And if I print, I get 10, because 10 is larger.
如果我打印出来 我得到的是10 因为10更大
Now, let's try to do the same thing in Java.
现在 让我们尝试在Java中做同样的事情
So again, I have my equivalent of the blank program.
所以 我有了我的空白程序的等价物
And at first, you might be tempted to start writing something about larger down here.
起初 你可能会想要开始在下面写一些关于更大的东西
But you've got to be careful. Remember, we said all code has to be part of a class.
但是你必须要小心  记住 我们说过所有的代码都必须是类的一部分
And this out here, not part of a class.
而这个在外面 不是类的一部分
So if I want to write my larger function, it has to live in the class.
所以如果我想写我的大型函数 它必须存在于类中
And I'm going to use the magic words.
而且我要使用魔法词
I look at this program, and it seems like, well, these words are in red.
我看着这个程序 感觉好像 嗯 这些词是红色的
So maybe I'll just copy that and hope something good happens.
所以也许我只是复制它 希望发生一些好事
I'll write, oops, I absolutely did not mean to write that.
我会写 哎呀 我绝对不是故意要写那个的
OK.
好的
OK, so I'll write public static, and then I'll write the name of the function, which is larger.
好的 那我会写public static 然后我会写函数的名字 叫larger
And I'll pass in x and y. OK, luckily, none of the TAs noticed.
然后我会传入x和y 好的 幸运的是 没有TA注意到
OK, so I'll write public static larger x and y. And then I'll say, if x is greater than y, I'll return x. Otherwise, I'll return y. OK, looks pretty good.
好的 那我会写public static larger x和y 然后我会说 如果x>y 我会返回x 否则 我会返回y 好的 看起来挺不错的
So maybe I'll give it a shot.
所以也许我会试一试
And I'll say, let's try to print out larger of negative 5 and 10.
然后我会说 让我们尝试打印出-5和10中较大的那个
And if I compile it, I get, uh-oh, some more errors.
如果我编译它 我会得到一些错误
And it says, well, you haven't told me what type x is.
它说 嗯 你没有告诉我x是什么类型
You also haven't told me what type y is.
你也没有告诉我y是什么类型
And in fact, Java also wants to know what variable type does the larger function return.
事实上 Java也想知道更大函数返回什么变量类型
So Java expects types for the arguments to the function and the return value of the function.
所以Java期望函数参数和函数返回值的类型
So I'm going to say x.
所以我会说x
You're an integer.
你是整数
Why?
为什么？
You are also an integer.
你也是一个整数
And this function, what does it return?
而这个函数呢 它返回什么？
It returns an integer.
它返回一个整数
And after I do that, now it'll tell me that the larger of negative 5 and 10 is 10.
然后我这样做之后 现在它会告诉我负5和10中较大的是10
That's my third demo.
这是我的第三个演示
OK, I screwed that one up, so don't applaud.
好吧 我搞砸了那个 所以不要鼓掌
All right.
好的
So let's reflect on what happened this time.
那么让我们反思一下这次发生的事情
So again, we saw that functions have to be declared as part of a class, because in Java, everything has to live in a class.
所以再次 我们看到函数必须作为类的一部分声明 因为在Java中 一切都必须存在于类中
To define a function in Java, we use the words public static, which I definitely have never misspelled ever.
在Java中定义函数 我们使用public static这几个词 我绝对从未拼错过
Later, we'll see alternate ways. But those are the magic words that you can use for today.
后面 我们会看到其他的方式  但这些是你今天可以使用的魔法词语
And you notice that when we define arguments to the function, like x and y, they had to have a declared type.
你注意到当我们为函数定义参数 比如x和y时 它们必须有一个声明的类型
And we also had to specify what type the return value of the function was, namely that the function returns an integer.
而且我们还必须指定函数的返回值类型 即函数返回一个整数
And one final note I'll make is that functions in Java can only return one value.
还有一点我要说的是 在Java中函数只能返回一个值
So you can't try.
所以你不能尝试
Everyone's laughing.
大家都在笑
Did I screw something up?
我搞砸了吗？
OK.
好的
Did my pants fall down or something?
是我的裤子掉了吗？
OK.
好的
No.
不
Great.
太好了
The final thing I'll note is that you can only return one value, so you can't return int and something else.
最后要注意的是你只能返回一个值 所以不能返回int和其他东西
What's so funny? I'm so confused.
有什么好笑的？ 我很困惑
Oh, the Zoom chat's getting wild. OK.
哦 Zoom聊天变得疯狂了
Got it.
知道了
No, yeah. Save that for after hours.
不 是的  把那个留到下班后吧
OK.
好的
Great.
很好
So that's larger.
所以这更大
OK.
好的
Any questions that are safe for work?
有哪些安全的问题吗？
OK.
好的
Great.
太好了
So let's reflect a little bit on what we've learned.
那么让我们稍微反思一下我们学到了什么
I'm glad you're all having fun.
我很高兴你们都玩得开心
Let's talk about reflections on Java. You're having too much fun.
让我们谈谈对 Java 的反思  你玩得太high了
I'm going to bore you a little bit with something about compilers and interpreters.
我来稍微跟你聊点编译器和解释器的事情 可能有点无聊
Uh, this part, if you're interested, there's a longer video on it.
嗯 如果你感兴趣的话 这部分还有一个更长的视频
But the summary is that before you can run the program, the compiler is going to check that all the types in the program match up.
但总的来说 在你运行程序之前 编译器会检查程序中的所有类型是否匹配
And only after the program is checked and all the types match up, can the program actually run.
只有在程序经过检查且所有类型匹配的情况下 程序才能真正运行
So
所以
Let's talk about how do you feel about this.
我们来谈谈你对此的感觉
So do you like that Java programs are statically typed?
你喜欢Java程序是静态类型的吗？
Do you not like it?
你不喜欢吗？
And there's not really a right answer here.
这里其实没有一个正确的答案
Some people like it.
有些人喜欢
Some people prefer the Python version, where I can make x equal to horse or whatever.
有些人更喜欢Python的版本 我可以把x设置为horse或者其他什么
And so it's kind of a matter of opinion.
所以这有点是个看法的问题
Here are some thoughts that we have.
这是我们的一些想法
As you program in Java, you're going to form some opinions of your own.
在你学Java的过程中 你会形成一些自己的看法
Some of you will love it.
有些人会喜欢它
Some of you will despise it and long for the days of 61A.
有些人会讨厌它 渴望回到61A的日子
It's kind of a matter of opinion.
这有点是主观看法的问题
So some things that I like about static typing, it catches certain types of errors.
关于静态类型 我喜欢的一些事情是 它可以捕捉某些类型的错误
So if you try to assign x to horse, Java will catch that for you ahead of time.
所以如果你试图将x赋值为horse Java会在你执行之前就为你捕捉到这个错误
It makes it easier to read about code, because if you say x is an integer, the person reading your code knows that it's always an integer.
它使得阅读代码变得更容易 因为如果你说x是一个整数 阅读你的代码的人就知道它总是一个整数
And it also turns out that by statically typing, code's just a little bit faster.
而且事实证明 通过静态类型 代码会快一点
So in general, Java's a faster language.
所以一般来说 Java是一种更快的语言
What are some things that we don't like about it?
我们不喜欢它的一些方面是什么？
Well, the code's a bit longer, so you already saw
嗯 代码有点长 所以你已经看到了
that just to write hello world, it took seven lines to write a hello world program compared to just one in Python.
仅仅是为了写个hello world 就要写七行代码 而在Python中只需一行
So code tends to be a little bit longer.
所以代码往往会长一点
You have to say more words to get the thing you want to happen.
你必须说更多的话才能让你想要的事情发生
And one more thing that we'll try to fix as the class goes on, but might be a problem for now, is that the code is a little bit less general.
还有一件事 在课程进行的过程中我们会尝试修复 但现在可能会有些问题 就是代码有点不够通用
So for example, if I wanted to use the larger function to compare decimals, like 5.5,
比如说 如果我想用较大的函数来比较小数 比如 5.5
The program is not going to like it.
程序就不会喜欢
So if I try like 5.5, the program is going to say, you can't do that.
所以如果我尝试使用 5.5 程序会说 你不能那样做
Negative 5.5 is not an integer.
负 5.5 不是整数
I also realized the title of the slide is gone.
我还注意到幻灯片的标题不见了
Someone's getting fired.
有人要被炒鱿鱼了
There it is.
就是这样
Just kidding.
开个玩笑
Questions on Java, reflection, anything else you'd like to know about it?
关于Java、反射 还有其他你想了解的吗？
Here comes the fun part.
接下来是有趣的部分
So this part we made from scratch this semester based on some feedback from last semester.
所以这部分是我们本学期根据上学期的一些反馈从零开始制作的
You are the first people in history to ever see this part of the lecture.
你们是历史上第一批看到讲座这一部分的人
And if we screw up, we'll screw it up together.
如果我们搞砸了 我们会一起搞砸的
OK, so let's take a look.
好的 那我们来看看
So object-oriented programming.
所以面向对象编程
Hopefully this is all review from 61A and hopefully you'll be like bored to tears by it.
希望这在 61A 课上已经复习过了 而且你们会觉得无聊到要流泪
But if not, let's go over it just to make sure we're all on the same page.
但如果没有 让我们过一遍 确保我们都理解一致
So hopefully you've seen before that object oriented programming is a model for organizing programs, and it gives us two really great features.
所以希望你之前见过面向对象编程是用来组织程序的一种模型 它给了我们两个非常棒的特性
One of them is modularity.
其中之一就是模块化
I can build one part of my program without worrying about the rest.
我可以构建程序的一部分而不担心其他部分
Then I can build another part of my program without worrying about the rest.
然后我可以构建程序的另一部分 而不必担心其余部分
And at the end, they'll all fit together in this beautiful way.
最后 它们都将以这种美妙的方式拼合在一起
So this way, I don't have to worry about the whole program at once.
这样 我就不必一次性担心整个程序
I can build little pieces at once and then put them all together.
我可以一次构建一点点 然后把它们都放在一起
And that's going to allow me to build really big, complicated things.
这将使我能够构建非常庞大、复杂的东西
It's also nice for data abstraction, which is hopefully another idea from 61A.
这也对数据抽象很有帮助 这也是从61A课程中学到的另一个概念
And the idea here is that you can interact with an object without knowing its internal implementations.
这里的思想是 你可以与对象进行交互 而不必了解其内部实现
And this is a big idea that we'll come back to over and over again in this class.
这是一个很重要的概念 我们在这堂课上会一次又一次地回到这个概念
What's an object?
什么是对象？
Hopefully, again, somewhat familiar from 61A or CS88.
希望你们从61A或CS88中再次听到会有些熟悉的感觉
An object is going to bundle together the information and related behavior.
对象将信息和相关行为捆绑在一起
And the idea is that this object can keep track of some information.
这个想法是 这个对象可以跟踪一些信息
And you can also interact with the object by calling methods on it.
你也可以通过调用它的方法与对象进行交互
And how do we build objects?
那么我们如何构建对象呢？
Well, we write a class.
好的 我们写一个类
And that's like our blueprint for how to create a brand new object.
这就像我们创建全新对象的蓝图一样
And then I can write code to create instances of that class.
然后我可以编写代码来创建该类的实例
So I know this all kind of sounds abstract, so I'll jump in and write the demo.
我知道这听起来有点抽象 所以我会跳进去写演示
And in case you're wondering why this all sounds so familiar, it is because I totally plagiarized this slide from 61A.
如果你在想为什么这听起来那么熟悉 那是因为我完全抄袭了61A的这张幻灯片
So thank you, John. And please don't report me.
所以感谢你 John  请不要举报我
OK.
好的
Now let's write some object-oriented code.
现在让我们写一些面向对象的代码
So often when we write code, we want to write code to model features of the real world.
很多时候 当我们写代码时 我们想要写代码来模拟现实世界的特征
So I'm going to try to write a class that models an object in the real world.
所以我打算尝试写一个类来模拟现实世界中的一个对象
So I've chosen to make a car. You can choose to make other things.
我选择做一个车  你也可以选择做其他的东西
I think in your homework, you have something else.
我觉得在你的作业中 你有其他的东西
But I'll write a class to model a car.
但我会写一个类来模拟一辆车
So I'll say class car.
所以我会说class car
And the first thing I'm going to write is a constructor.
而我要写的第一件事就是一个构造函数
Sounds somewhat familiar, maybe not.
听起来有点熟悉 也许不完全是
The constructor tells us how to create a brand new object from scratch.
构造函数告诉我们如何从头开始创建一个全新的对象
So if someone says, I want a new car, well, what are the properties of the car?
所以如果有人说 我想要一辆新车 那么 车的属性是什么？
How do I set up the car when someone creates it for the first time?
当有人第一次创建它时 如何设置这辆车？
So let's write some code to set up my brand new car for the first time.
所以让我们写一些代码 第一次设置我的全新汽车
So in Python, the magic words to create a new car are the init method.
所以在Python中 创建新汽车的魔术词是init方法
This is the constructor.
这是构造函数
The constructor can take in additional arguments if you want.
构造函数可以接受额外的参数 如果你想要的话
So I'm going to give it one extra argument, m. And now I can start setting up what instance variables does the car have.
所以我要给它一个额外的参数 m 现在我可以开始设置汽车有哪些实例变量了
So when I set up a new car for the first time, what are its properties?
所以当我第一次为新汽车设置时 它有哪些属性呢？
when the car first starts up.
当汽车第一次启动时
So maybe the car will have, I don't know, like a model.
也许汽车会有 我不知道 像一个型号
So what year is it?
那么它是哪一年的？
What kind of car is it?
它是什么牌子的车？
And that could be something that the user supplies as an argument when they create the car for the first time.
这可能是用户在第一次创建汽车时作为参数提供的内容
Well, what else do cars have?
嗯 汽车还有什么其他东西？
I don't know about you. I feel like most cars have wheels.
我不知道你怎么想  我觉得大多数汽车都有轮子
So maybe I'll say, when you make a new car for the first time, it's got four wheels.
也许我会说 当你第一次制造一辆新车时 它有四个车轮
OK, seems like a pretty good car.
好的 看起来是一辆相当不错的车
That would be how I construct a new car in Python.
这就是我用Python构建新车的方式
And again, this is just the blueprint.
而且 这只是蓝图
So I haven't actually made any cars.
所以我实际上还没有制造任何车
I'm just writing a template for future users of the car class to create brand new cars from scratch.
我只是在为未来的汽车类用户编写模板 让他们可以从零开始创建全新的汽车
OK, now let's do it in Java.
好的 现在让我们用Java来做
So in Java, I'm going to write public class car.
所以在 Java 中 我要写 public class car
We know those are the magic words from before.
我们知道这些是之前的魔术词
And again, I'm going to write a constructor that tells me how to create a brand new car from scratch.
而且 我要再次写一个构造函数 告诉我如何从头开始创建一辆全新的汽车
And at this point, the syntax is going to get a little bit messy, so don't worry too much about every specific word and letter.
在这一点上 语法会变得有点凌乱 所以不要太担心每个具体的单词和字母
As long as you get the high-level idea of how I'm creating and working with objects, then you should be all set.
只要你理解我是如何创建和使用对象的高层次概念 那么你应该没问题了
So let's go through and make a new car.
所以让我们来创建一辆新车吧
Or let's write a method for how to make a new car.
或者让我们写一个创建新车的方法
So I'll write public car.
那我就写public汽车
So here, I'm not using the magic word init.
所以在这里 我不使用魔术词init
I'm using the same name of the class.
我使用的是类的相同名称
Here's car.
这是汽车
And again, I can give it some arguments like m. And I'll say, instead of saying self, which is a reference to the current car object being created here, I will say this.
而且 我可以给它一些参数 比如m 我会说 不是说self 这是指正在创建的当前汽车对象的引用 我会说this
which is the Java special word for the current object being referenced.
这是Java特殊词 表示当前正在引用的对象
And I'll say, OK, your model is whatever the user specified, and you have four wheels.
我会说 好的 你的模型就是用户指定的 而且有四个轮子
So stare at this a little bit from your 20 minutes of Java.
所以从你的20分钟Java中仔细看一下这个
Does something seem a little bit wrong here?
这里有点不对劲吗？
Well, there's a couple of things that's wrong.
嗯 有几件事情是错的
One thing is, if I declare that there's a variable m, I have to tell you what type it is, unlike in Python.
一件事是 如果我声明有一个变量m 我必须告诉你它是什么类型 不像在Python中那样
So I have to say m, you're a string.
所以我必须说m 你是一个字符串
And in fact, If I try to compile this, it's going to complain and say, actually, I don't even know what wheels is.
实际上  如果我尝试编译这个 它会抱怨并说 实际上 我甚至不知道wheels是什么
I don't know what model is.
我不知道是什么型号
So if you have instance variables in Java, you have to declare those, too.
所以在Java中如果有实例变量 你也必须声明它们
You have to say, what does a car have?
你必须说 一辆车有什么？
A car has a model, and it's a string.
一辆车有一个型号 而且是一个字符串
What else does a car have?
一辆车还有什么？
It has a number of wheels, and that's 4.
它有一些车轮 总共4个
OK, so I've written my blueprint for how someone will create a brand new car.
好的 所以我已经写好了创建一辆全新汽车的蓝图
And in the process, I've also defined instance variables that tell me what are the properties of my new car.
而且在这个过程中 我还定义了实例变量 告诉我我的新车的属性是什么
You can also have other things here.
这里也可以有其他东西
You could have, I don't know, color.
你可以有 我不知道 颜色
You could have driver, whatever you want.
你可以有驾驶员 随你想要的
But today, it's models and wheels.
但今天 谈的是车型和轮胎
Questions on the constructor, how it was made?
对于构造函数有什么问题 它是如何制作的？
OK, if you zoned out, I have a slide that writes down most of what I just said.
好的 如果你走神了 我有一张幻灯片写下了我刚刚说的大部分内容
OK.
好的
Let's keep going.
继续前进吧
So I've built my brand new car or written a method or a constructor that tells me how to create a new car.
所以我已经建造了我的全新汽车 或者编写了一个方法或构造函数 告诉我如何创建一辆新汽车
But I would like this car to do stuff.
但我想让这辆车做点事情
So let's make the car do stuff.
所以让我们让这辆车做点事情
What are some things that cars do?
汽车会做些什么事情呢？
Class.
class
Do cars do anything?
汽车有什么作用吗？
Drive, OK, brilliant.
驾驶 好的 太棒了
Let's have a drive method for the car.
我们为汽车添加一个驾驶方法吧
So how should the car drive?
那么汽车应该怎么驾驶呢？
Well, I'm going to be a little bit lazy, and I'm just going to have the car make a noise to indicate that it's driving.
嗯 我会有点懒 就让汽车发出声音来表示它在行驶
So maybe I'll say, OK, the car is going vroom.
也许我会说 好的 汽车发出嗡嗡声
You've paid thousands of dollars to come hear me say, car goes vroom.
你花了成千上万美元来听我说 汽车发出嗡嗡声
Okay, looks pretty good.
好的 看起来挺不错的
But there is one problem, which is, well, I don't know about you, but my understanding is that cars can only drive if they have the requisite number of wheels.
但有一个问题 就是 嗯 我不知道你怎么看 但我的理解是汽车只有在拥有足够数量的轮子时才能行驶
So I'm gonna add one little if statement that says, actually, if the current car, so when I say self.wheels, I'm referring to the current car being referenced, because this is a blueprint for all cars that I ever wanna create.
所以我要添加一个小的if语句 实际上 如果当前的汽车 当我说self.wheels时 我是在引用当前正在引用的汽车 因为这是我想要创建的所有汽车的蓝图
If there are fewer than four wheels, the car shouldn't drive, and I should let the user know that.
如果轮子少于四个 那么汽车就不应该行驶 并且我应该让用户知道这一点
So what should I say?
那我应该说什么呢？
What should I say?
我应该说什么呢？
OK, I heard a lot of suggestions.
好的 我听到了很多建议
Someone give me one.
有人给我一个
OK, no go vroom.
好的 不会出现问题
Brilliant.
太棒了
OK.
好的
Looks good.
看起来不错
I like it.
我喜欢
OK, so there's my function. Now I'm going to try to write the same thing in Java.
好的 这就是我的函数  现在我要尝试用Java写同样的东西
So I'll say, again, some magic words to define a function.
所以我会再次说一些魔法词来定义一个函数
More on this next time.
下次会详细解释
And I'll say drive.
然后我会说驱动
This time it hasn't taken any arguments.
这次它没有接受任何参数
And I'll say, if this.wheels is less than 4, that means this car do not go vroom.
我会说 如果 this.wheels < 4 那意味着这辆车不会发动
So we will tell the user, this car no go vroom.
我们会告诉用户 这辆车开不动了
OK, no go vroom.
好的 开不动了
Great.
太好了
Otherwise, this car has the right number of wheels, so we can have it drive.
除此之外 这车轮子数量正好 可以让它开起来
So we'll have it go vroom.
我们会让它开起来
Oops, this.model, go vroom.
哎呀 this.model 能开动
OK.
好的
Looks pretty good.
看起来相当不错
So there's my function for drive.
所以这是我的驱动函数
Again, one tiny thing we have to fix, which is, remember in Java, when I write a function, I have to tell you what does that function return.
再次 我们必须修复一件小事 就是 记住在Java中 当我写一个函数时 我必须告诉你这个函数返回什么
And in this case, the drive function isn't returning anything.
在这种情况下 驱动函数没有返回任何内容
It's printing stuff out for the user, but it doesn't actually have a return value.
它为用户打印一些东西 但实际上没有返回值
And the way I'm going to indicate that is using the magic word void.
我要用魔术词语void来表示这一点
That means nothing gets returned.
这意味着没有东西被返回
All right, that's my drive function.
好的 这就是我的驱动功能
It's looking pretty good.
看起来相当不错
So let's think about what else cars can do.
那么让我们想想汽车还能做什么
Well, one thing you might want to do when you're building a class, maybe I want the user to be able to tell me, or maybe I want the user to be able to request, how many wheels are on this car?
嗯 构建一个类时 你可能想做的一件事是 也许我希望用户能够告诉我 或者也许我希望用户能够请求 这辆汽车有多少个轮子？
Maybe they should be able to know.
也许他们应该知道
So maybe I'll write a function that's like, tell me how many wheels are on this car.
所以也许我会写一个函数 像是 告诉我这辆车有多少个轮子
OK, there's the function.
好的 这就是函数
What should it do?
它应该做什么？
It should tell me how many wheels are on the car.
它应该告诉我车上有几个轮子
Let's write it in Java, public.
让我们用Java来写 public
And again, I have to say what the function returns.
再说一次 我得说一下这个函数返回什么
Here, it's going to return an integer, because the number of wheels is an integer.
在这里 它将返回一个整数 因为轮子的数量是一个整数
And I'll say get numWheels.
然后我会说getNumWheels
And it will return the number of wheels.
它会返回轮子的数量
OK, looks pretty good. This all looks pretty good.
好的 看起来不错  这一切看起来都很不错
It looks like my car is working.
我的车看起来运作正常
It's driving.
它在行驶
It's making noises.
它在发出声音
It's vrooming.
它发出了'嗡嗡'的声音
But maybe one more thing that we can do with objects is we can manipulate their state.
但我们可能还能对对象做一件事 就是改变它们的状态
So when people call functions or methods on an object, you can also change how the object behaves, or you can change the state of the object.
所以当人们在对象上调用函数或方法时 你也可以改变对象的行为 或者你可以改变对象的状态
So here's something that I don't recommend doing, but it's something you can do with your car.
所以这里有件事我不建议做 但这是你可以用你的车做的事情
One thing you could do is you could drive it into a ditch.
你可以做的一件事是把它开进沟里
And I don't recommend doing that.
我不建议那样做
But maybe if you drive it into a ditch, you'll lose some wheels.
但也许如果你把它开进沟里 你会丢失一些车轮
So not a great idea.
所以不是一个好主意
But that's something you could do.
但这是你可以做的事情
And maybe when you do that, your car is going to lose some wheels.
也许当你这样做时 你的车会失去一些轮子
So I'll say self.wheels minus however many wheels the user says you lost by driving into this ditch.
所以我会说self.wheels减去用户说你因为开进这个沟而失去的轮子的数量
Again, I can write the same thing in Java.
再说一遍 我可以用Java写同样的东西
I can say public.
我可以说public
Well, this function is not really returning anything.
嗯 这个函数实际上并没有返回任何东西
So I'll say void, indicating no return value.
所以我会说void 表示没有返回值
It's going to drive into a ditch, and it's going to take the number of wheels lost.
它会开进沟里 然后会记录失去的轮子的数量
Again, I have to say int, because I have to specify what type.
再说一遍 我得说 int 因为我得指定类型
What happens when I drive into a ditch?
我开车掉进沟里会发生什么？
Well, the number of wheels decreases by however many wheels the user tells me they've lost.
嗯 车轮数量会减少 减少的数量是用户告诉我的
Looks pretty good.
看起来相当不错
In addition to functions that make the car vroom and stuff and make noise, the car can also have its instance variables modified, for example, when you drive into a ditch.
除了使车辆发动并发出声音之类的功能外 车辆还可以修改其实例变量 例如当你开车掉进沟里时
Okay, looks pretty good.
好的 看起来相当不错
Any questions so far before I start using the car?
在我开始使用车辆之前有什么问题吗？
Okay, question number one. Yeah, that's a good question.
好的 第一个问题  嗯 这是一个好问题
Should I put an else statement? I could.
我应该放一个else语句吗？ 我可以的
I could also put a return here so that it ends early.
我也可以在这里放一个return 这样它就提前结束了
That's a good point.
这是一个很好的观点
Because if car no go vroom, it should not go vroom.
因为如果车不会嗡嗡作响 它就不应该嗡嗡作响
OK, other questions?
好的 还有其他问题吗？
One more? Did I say self instead of this?
还有一个吗？ 是我说了self而不是this吗？
Ah, that's the thing about programming in two languages at once.
啊 这就是同时用两种语言编程的事情
You should try it sometime.
你也应该试试看
It's not very fun.
这不是很有趣
OK, other questions?
好的 还有其他问题吗？
A public on the left side of string and int. Oh, that's a good point.
左边有一个公共的字符串和整数  哦 这个观点不错
So if you would like to, you can.
所以如果你愿意的话 你可以
That's something we'll talk about when we talk more about classes.
这是我们更多地讨论类时会谈到的事情
But it's more of a syntactic quirk than something fundamental to objects.
但这更多的是一种语法上的怪癖 而不是对象的基本属性
Good catch, though. Other catches?
不过 你说得对  其他的发现吗？
OK, I'll take one more.
好的 我再来一个
Everyone else on Zoom.
其他人都在Zoom上
Not sure I totally follow the question.
不太确定我完全理解问题
Can you say it one more time, but louder?
你能再说一遍吗 声音大点吗？
Oh, you're asking what happens if I don't put this?
哦 你是在问如果我不放这个会发生什么？
That's a little bit out of scope for today.
那可能有点超出今天的范围
So maybe come ask us afterwards.
所以也许之后再来问我们吧
But for today, either is OK.
但是就今天来说 都可以
Good questions, though.
不过 问题很好
OK, so I've made my car.
好的 我已经制造好了我的车
Again, this is a blueprint for how a car should run.
再次强调 这是汽车应该运行的蓝图
It tells me about the car driving, tells me about attributes of the car.
它告诉我汽车的驾驶情况 告诉我汽车的属性
Now it's time to finally use a car.
现在是时候最终使用一辆汽车了
So I'm going to go out and get myself a brand new car in imagination.
所以我要出去想象中得到一辆全新的汽车
OK, so I'll say C1 equals, and I'm going to make a new car.
好的 那么我会说C1= 然后我要制造一辆新车
So I'll call the constructor car.
所以我会调用构造函数car
And now I have to pass an argument.
现在我必须传递一个参数
The car expects me to tell this new car what model it is.
这辆车希望我告诉它这辆新车是什么型号
I am no car expert, so someone has to tell me, what is the model of our CS61B brand new car?
我不是汽车专家 所以有人必须告诉我 我们CS61B全新汽车的型号是什么？
A what?
什么？
Civic Type R. A Civic Type R. Did I get that right?
Civic Type R  Civic Type R 我说得对吗？
Yeah.
好的
OK.
I'll take your word for it.
我相信你的话
All right.
好的
OK.
But I'm feeling really generous today.
但是我今天心情真好
I'm like the Oprah of 61B.
我就像 61B 的奥普拉
So you get a second car.
你弄了辆第二辆车
So what is your second car model? Toyota Camry.
你的第二辆车是什么型号？ Toyota Camry
OK.
好的
I offered you a car.
我给你提供了一辆车
And you took two very luxurious cars.
你却选了两辆非常豪华的车
OK. OK, well, we made our two cars.
好的 我们完成了我们的两辆车
They look pretty good.
它们看起来相当不错
So now we can start using them.
所以现在我们可以开始使用它们了
So maybe we'll take our Civic Type R out for a drive.
也许我们会开我们的思域Type R出去兜风
OK, pretty good.
好的 相当不错
Maybe we get a bit clumsy, and we drive our Civic Type R into a ditch, and it loses a couple wheels.
也许我们有点笨拙 把我们的思域Type R开进沟里 丢了几个车轮
Uh-oh.
哎呀
And then I try to drive it again later.
然后我稍后再试着开车
OK, so that looks pretty good.
好的 看起来挺不错的
And one thing I'll add at the end is maybe I'm curious, after I drive my Civic Type R into a ditch, does the Toyota Camry still have any wheels left on it?
最后 我想补充一件事 也许我会好奇 当我把我的Civic Type R开进沟里时 Toyota Camry上还有没有轮子？
So I'll print that out just to see how many wheels it has.
所以我会打印出来看看它有多少个轮子
I'm sure people are having scintillating discussions in the Zoom chat.
我确信人们在Zoom聊天中正在进行着引人入胜的讨论
Great, so there's my demo. I'll run it just to make sure it works.
太棒了 这就是我的演示  我会运行它 只是为了确保它能正常工作
And it says the Civic type part goes vroom because I drove it, and then because I drove it into a ditch.
而且它说 Civic 类型的零件会因为我开过它 然后因为我把它开进了沟里
It's no go vroom the second time.
第二次它就不会发动了
But one thing you'll notice is that the second card that I created, the Toyota Camry only had, or still has, four wheels because I never drove it into a ditch.
但你会注意到的一件事是 我创建的第二张卡 丰田凯美瑞只有 或者仍然有 四个车轮 因为我从未把它开进沟里
So these objects are updating their internal state as I call functions on them, which is pretty cool.
所以这些对象在我调用它们的函数时更新它们的内部状态 这很酷
All right, I'm going to write one more in Java, since you're all getting so antsy, and then we'll call it a day.
好的 我要再用 Java 写一个 因为你们都变得如此焦躁不安 然后我们就收工了
So in Java, I want to write the code out here, but I kind of can't do that, because it's outside of a class.
所以在 Java 中 我想在这里写出代码 但我有点做不到 因为这是在类的外部
So in Java, this code that's outside of the class, I can't put it outside of a class, so it has to live in Maine.
在Java中 这段代码在类外部 我不能把它放在类外部 所以它必须存在于Maine
Am I out of time?
我时间到了吗？
People are getting so antsy.
人们变得如此焦躁不安
You are not out of time. Please do not wait.
你还没有用完时间  请不要等待
Oh, I'm not out of time.
哦 我还有几分钟
Aha, I still have you captive for a couple of minutes.
啊哈 我还能抓住你几分钟
Five minutes.
五分钟
Awesome, OK.
太好了 好的
It's OK.
没问题
They're not interested in the cars.
他们对车不感兴趣
I'm going to write the car methods.
我打算编写汽车方法
So I will say C1 equals shh.
所以我会说C1=car
So rowdy today.
今天真吵
Great.
太棒了
So I'll write my first car.
那我就写我的第一辆车了
Great.
太棒了
No cars for the person who left.
留下的人没有车了
That person didn't know I was actually going to give the cars away, but not anymore.
那个人不知道我其实要送走这些车 但现在不是了
Okay, so I'll write the cars.
好的 那我就写这些车
I'll have the first one drive just like before.
我会让第一辆车像以前一样开
It's not super interesting.
这个不是特别有趣
I'll have the first one drive into the ditch again, and then we'll see if it still drives after that.
我会让第一个车再次开进沟里 然后我们看看它还能不能开
And just like before, just to make sure that changing the first one didn't change the second one, I'll just check how many the second car has just in case.
就像以前一样 为了确保更改第一个不会更改第二个 我会检查第二辆车有多少 以防万一
This is almost correct.
这几乎正确
There's two little syntactic quirks I got to solve.
有两个小的句法怪癖我得解决
So one of them is that when I want to use the C1 and C2 variables, what do I have to do?
其中一个是当我想使用C1和C2变量时 我该怎么办？
I have to declare that they exist.
我得声明它们存在
So I have to say, I declare there's a variable called C1 that I can hold a car, and there's also a variable C2 that can hold a car.
所以我得说 我声明有一个叫做C1的变量 可以容纳一辆车 还有一个叫做C2的变量 可以容纳一辆车
And only after I write that can I use those two variables.
而且只有在我写了那个之后 我才能使用这两个变量
One final little thing in Java, if you're creating a new object, Java needs to know that you're creating a new object.
在Java中有最后一点小事 如果你正在创建一个新对象 Java需要知道你正在创建一个新对象
So you give it this little new keyword.
所以你给它这个小小的new关键字
And again, those are tiny little syntactic quirks.
而且 这些只是微小的语法怪癖
You'll get used to them as you write more Java.
随着你写更多的Java 你会习惯它们
But the punchline is, I've written this in Java.
但是 要点是 我已经用Java写过这个
And in Java, my civic type arg of room, then a no go of room, then it's four.
在Java中 我的 civic 类型 R go vroom 然后一个 R no go vroom 然后就是4
Hold on, hold on.
等一下 等一下
I have one more thing to show you.
我还有一件事要给你看
You're so antsy.
你真是坐立不安
OK.
好的
So we talked about methods.
所以我们谈论了方法
A method is a fancy name for an object living inside of a class.
方法是指存在于类内的对象的一个花哨的名称
You came in here if you wanted to be loud, we should have kicked you out earlier.
你进来就是想吵 我们早就该把你赶出去了
Okay, so.
好的
One final thing I'll note in Java is you might get confused by the this keyword.
在Java中 我要注意的最后一件事是 你可能会被this关键字搞糊涂
Because in Java, it turns out Java is a pretty smart language.
因为在Java中 事实证明Java是一门相当聪明的语言
And in fact, if you actually remove this dot and you simply say wheels, Java is pretty smart.
实际上 如果你去掉这个点 只是说wheels Java是相当聪明的
And it'll realize that in this class, there's only one thing called wheels.
它会意识到在这个类中只有一件叫做wheels的东西
It's right there.
就在那儿
So this will also work just fine.
这样也完全可以
So except in exceptional cases where you have multiple variables that have the same name or something confusing,
所以除非有特殊情况 你有多个变量具有相同的名称或者什么令人困惑的东西
This dot syntax is actually a little bit optional.
这个点语法实际上有点可选的
People always get confused by it.
人们总是对此感到困惑
So there's your slide to hopefully clear it up.
所以这就是你的幻灯片 希望能澄清一下
Okay, I guess I used gas in the original demo and this time it was wheels falling off.
好的 我想在原始演示中我使用了气体 这次是车轮脱落
Oh well.
噢 好吧
Okay, we talked about how you create objects.
好的 我们谈过了如何创建对象
There's the code for, I guess I chose a Honda Civic as well.
这是代码 我猜我也选择了一辆本田思域
So we are all using our poverty cars together.
所以我们都在用我们的破车
And we talked about how you can access an object using dot notation.
我们还谈过了如何使用点符号访问对象
So you can say C1, that's the car, and then a dot, and then accessing the methods.
所以你可以说C1 那就是汽车 然后是一个点 然后是访问方法
Okay, final thing before you all go is you have watched me write a lot of Java, and I don't expect you to go out and start programming cars just because you've watched me program one.
好的 在你们离开之前最后一件事是你们看着我写了很多Java 我不指望你们出去开始编程汽车 只是因为你们看着我编程了一辆
So, in order to get used to Java, you're gonna have to write some yourself.
所以 为了熟悉Java 你得自己写一些
So your first job today is to go home, write some Java, we'll come back on Friday, and we'll write some more Java.
所以你今天的第一项任务就是回家 写一些Java 我们周五再来 然后写更多Java
Okay, bye.
好的 再见
What's the question?
问题是什么？